redux.com 2009-02-14

# Redux Privacy Policy

**Redux Privacy Policy**

Redux, Inc. (" **Redux** ") has developed a service that enables users to connect with another. Users of our service can share information, content, photos, videos or other materials with other users (collectively, " **User Content** ") and can interact, email, meet or otherwise communicate with other users (" **User Conduct** ").  When you use our service, Redux has access to, and in many cases can monitor, your User Content and User Conduct. 

Redux recognizes that you trust us to act in a responsible manner with any personal information, User Content or User Conduct information we learn about you when you use our service and we are committed to respecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, use and disclose information (including but not limited to your personal information, User Content and User Conduct) we receive when you visit and use [www.redux.com](http://www.redux.com/), [www.flickim.com](http://www.flickim.com/) and [www.flick.im](http://www.flick.im/) (collectively, the " **Sites** "), when you access and use any service, application, software, feature, material, information or other content appearing on the Sites or offered by Redux (the " **Services** ").

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time. We will notify you of any material changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on the Sites or through a message sent to your registered mobile phone number. Unless we provide you with separate notice and an opportunity to opt out, information will be treated in accordance with the policy that was in place when the information was collected. You are advised to consult this Privacy Policy regularly for any changes.

As used in this Privacy Policy, the terms "using" and "processing" information include using cookies on a computer, subjecting the information to statistical or other analysis and using or handling information in any way, including, but not limited to collecting, storing, evaluating, modifying, deleting, using, combining, disclosing and transferring information within our organization or among our affiliates within the United States or internationally.

**Information Collection & Use**

Our primary goals in collecting information are to provide and improve our Sites and Services, to administer your subscription and to enable users to enjoy and easily navigate and use the Sites and Services.

**(i)        Personally Identifiable Information**

  * When you choose to register, subscribe to any or all of our Services or create your own profile webpage on our Sites, we will ask you for certain information that can be used to contact or identify you and administer your account (" **Personal Information** "). Personal Information includes, but is not limited to, your name, date of birth, account passwords, phone number, credit card or other billing information, email address, home and business postal addresses and your privacy preferences. If you sign up to receive promotional offers or alerts via text messaging, any mobile number you provide us to receive such offers or alerts will be collected by Redux as Personal Information. Redux may also request that you provide Personal Information when you order additional services (for example, premium functionality), when you request promotional information, when you complete customer surveys, when you participate in contests, when you call our customer support line and if you contact or interact with us. Finally, when you apply for a job and provide us with Personal Information, we will collect such information. Your account passwords, phone number, credit card and other billing information will be encrypted on our server. 

  * Redux uses your Personal Information (in some cases, in conjunction with your Site Usage Information and/or in conjunction with your User Content Information) mainly to provide the Services you request, complete your transactions, resolve disputes and communicate with you. For example, Redux may use your Personal Information in order to enable us to process and validate your account and any subscription information, to bill for any Services, to contact you regarding your account or Services you have selected to use, to contact you about new or existing products and services or special offers that may be of interest to you, to process and charge any fees due, to verify your identity or customer qualifications as may be required, to detect and protect us against error, fraud or criminal activity, to enforce our terms of use, to respond to any communications you send us or to provide you with any relevant or requested information. If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive certain communications from us, please follow the instructions provided in any of the communications or update your "user preferences" information (see " **Changing or Deleting Information** " below).

  * PLEASE BE AWARE that when you register through the Sites and submit Personal Information to create a user profile, other users of the Site and Services may be able to see your name, date of birth, zip code, gender and/or relationship status. You can choose what Personal Information you provide as part of your user profile and in some cases you can choose whether to share that information publicly on the Sites by making selections via the "user preferences" section of your profile webpage. Providing such information is voluntary and should correlate with the degree of interaction you want to have with other users. We recommend that you guard your anonymity and sensitive information carefully and that you not provide any information that you would not like others to be able to see or view publicly, since that could allow others to identify you.

**(ii)       Site Usage Information**

  * Our Sites are designed so that visitors may browse it without the collection of any personally identifiable information (except for such visitor's internet protocol (IP) address). When you visit the Sites, we may collect information indirectly and automatically (through the use of cookies, as described below) about your Site activity, including the geographic location of the IP address you are using to access the internet, the type of browser used, platform type, referring/exit pages and date/time information (" **Site Usage Information** "). 

  * Redux uses Site Usage Information for internal purposes such as to administer, improve and customize the Sites, to help Redux understand and analyze how the Sites are being used, to track aggregate Site usage, to provide technical administration, to increase the Sites' functionality and user-friendliness and to better tailor the Sites to our visitors' needs. For example, some information is collected so that when you visit the Sites again, it will recognize you and serve advertisements and other information appropriate to your interests. 

**(iii)       User Information**

  * Once you have opened an account and begin to use the Services, we will collect information about your User Content and User Conduct during your use of the Sites and Services (collectively, " **User Information** "). User Information includes such information as what types of User Content you have shared with others (including for example ratings you provide to other users, questions you answer, messages and files you post on other users' profiles and communications you have with other users), what types of User Content from other viewers you have viewed or requested, what types of User Conduct you have engaged in, and what types of User Conduct others have engaged with you, which websites and programs you access or download when using the Sites or Services, how long you visit such websites and use such programs, your activities (such as products purchased or advertisements viewed), which specific areas of a website or webpage you use and for how long, websites you bookmark, search terms you use, referring/exit pages, browser and platform types, the geographic location in which you are using the Sites and Services. By using our Site and Services and/or accepting our Terms of Use (which includes acceptance of this Privacy Policy), you have given us your express consent to collect and use User Information. 

  * Redux uses User Information to offer you personalized Sites and Services. User Information permits us to recommend people, products, activities, events and services that we believe will be of interest to you, personalize your viewing, Sites and Services usage, select targeted advertisements or other promotions for you and offer you local content and advertising information. 

  * PLEASE BE AWARE that your User Information, when viewed by others, may reveal your identity, whether or not you have chosen to include Personal Information with such User Information.

**Interacting with other Users**

  * PLEASE BE AWARE that when you use the Site and Services to engage in activities with other users (for example, by posting information about yourself, communicating, rating people or events, interacting, meeting, corresponding, etc.), other users have access to that information. Hence, when you voluntarily post Personal Information or User Content to certain areas of the Sites or through the Services - such as to rating areas, journals, weblogs, message boards, classifieds, forums and other event areas, and when you elect to engage in a transaction, communication or other User Conduct with another user by using the Sites or Services, other users (and in some cases the public at large) can see, collect and use that information. The fact that the Sites and Services permit you to communicate, interact with or link to other users is not an endorsement, authorization or representation of our affiliation with those users, nor is it an endorsement of their privacy or information security policies or practices. Redux does not exercise control over other users. Other users with whom you interact may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, and may collect data or solicit personal information from you. Such users follow different rules regarding the use or disclosure of the personal information you submit to them. We encourage you to be careful how you interact with other users. 

  * While it is against the Redux Terms of Use for other users to collect this information, it is possible that it may be wrongly redistributed on the internet.  You understand and acknowledge that, even after removal, copies of any information you have provided others may remain viewable in cached and archived pages or if other users have copied or stored such information. 

  * If you choose to use our invitation service to tell a friend about our Site, we will ask you for information needed to send the invitation, such as your friend's email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email or instant message inviting him or her to visit the site. The Site stores this information to send this one-time invitation, to register a friend connection if your invitation is accepted, and to track the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact us at remove@redux.com to request that we remove this information from our database.

**Cookies**

  * We use "cookies" on our Sites to collect information. A cookie is a small data or text file that we transfer to your computer's hard disk for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies for two purposes. First, we utilize persistent cookies to save your registration and/or user ID and login password for future logins to the Sites or use of the Services and for utilizing the chat functions on the Site and Services. Second, we utilize session ID cookies to enable certain features of the Sites or Services, to better understand how you interact with the Sites and Services and to monitor aggregate usage and web traffic routing on the Sites and Services (for example, such as noting the web pages you visit, the links you click on and the searches you conduct on our Site). Unlike persistent cookies, session cookies are deleted from your computer when you log off from the Sites and close your computer browser. For security purposes, we will encrypt any usernames, passwords and other account-related data that we store in such cookies.

  * Third party advertisers on the Sites may also place or read cookies on your computer's browser, which permit them to collect information about users who view or interact with their advertisements. Such third party advertisers may collect information about how and from which location you, or others who are using your computer, viewed and/or clicked on the advertisements they deliver, and possibly associate this information with your subsequent visits to the advertised websites. They also may combine this information with personal information they collect from you. The collection and use of that information is subject to the third party's privacy policy.

  * You can instruct your browser, by changing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions of the Sites or all (or any) functionality of the Services.

**Phishing**

Identity theft and the practice currently known as "phishing" are of great concern to Redux. Safeguarding information to help protect you from identity theft is a top priority. We do not and will not, at any time, request your credit card information, your account ID, login password, or national identification numbers in a non-secure or unsolicited e-mail or telephone communication. For more information about phishing, visit the Federal Trade Commission's website.

**Information Sharing and Disclosure**

We do not share Personal Information, Site Usage Information and/or User Information with third parties except as follows:

  * **Service Providers.** We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Sites and Services, to provide the Sites and Services on our behalf, to perform Site-related services (e.g., without limitation, bill or credit card payment processing, maintenance services, database management, web analytics and improvement of the Sites' features) or to assist us in analyzing how our Sites and Services are used. These third parties have access to your Personal Information, Site Usage Information and/or User Information only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

  * **Aggregate Information and Non-Identifying Information.** We may share aggregated Site Usage Information and/or User Information that does not include Personal Information and we may otherwise disclose User Information with third parties (including suppliers, advertisers, research companies and other organizations) for industry analysis, demographic profiling and other purposes. Any information shared in these contexts will not contain your Personal Information.

  * **Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement.** Redux cooperates with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We will disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process (including but not limited to subpoenas), to protect the property and rights of Redux or a third party, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop activity we may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, any illegal, unethical or legally actionable activity. 

  * **Business Transfers.** Redux may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of its assets, including your Personal Information, in connection with a merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets or in the event of bankruptcy. Redux will notify you before transferring your information to a new entity as part of a merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of some or all of its assets if the new entity's processing of your information will materially differ from that set forth in this Privacy Policy." This option, which would take the place of the bracketed sentence, may not be legally valid in some international jurisdictions, but experience dictates that acquiring entities often want to purchase personal information and handle it under their own privacy policy. If your entity sees itself later selling personal information to such an entity, this version of the provision could decrease exposure in the US. 

**Changing or Deleting Your Information**

All subscribers to our Sites may review, update, correct or delete the Personal Information in their registration profile by contacting us. If you completely delete all such information, then your account may become deactivated. If you would like us to delete your record in our system, please contact us and we will attempt to accommodate your request if we do not have any legal obligation to retain the record. See below for privacy contact information. From time to time, we may contact you by mail, email or telephone to tell you about additional products or services that we or third parties may offer. If you do not wish to receive such calls or promotional materials, please contact us and we will attempt to accommodate your request.

**Security**

Redux is concerned with safeguarding your information. We employ a variety of industry-standard administrative, physical and electronic security measures designed to protect your information from unauthorized access. We will make any legally required disclosures of any breach of the security, confidentiality or integrity of your unencrypted electronically stored "personal data" (as defined in applicable state statutes on security breach notification) to you via email or conspicuous posting on the Sites in the most expedient time possible and without unreasonable delay, insofar as consistent with (i) the legitimate needs of law enforcement or (ii) any measures necessary to determine the scope of the breach and restore the reasonable integrity of the data system. 

**International Transfers**

Your information may be transferred to - and maintained on - computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. If you are located outside the United States and choose to provide information to us, Redux transfers Personal Information to the United States and processes it there. Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

**Links to Other Sites**

Our Sites contain links to other websites. If you choose to visit an advertiser by "clicking on" a banner ad or other type of advertisement, or click on another third party link, you will be directed to that third party's website. The fact that the Sites permit you to link to a website or present a banner ad or other type of advertisement is not an endorsement, authorization or representation of our affiliation with that third party, nor is it an endorsement of their privacy or information security policies or practices. We do not exercise control over third party websites. These other websites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you. Other sites follow different rules regarding the use or disclosure of the personal information you submit to them. We encourage you to read the privacy policies or statements of the other websites you visit. 

**Our Policy Towards Children**

The Sites and use of the Services are not directed to children under twenty-one (21) years. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with Personal Information without their consent, he or she should contact us at privacy@redux.com. If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with Personal Information, we will delete such information from our files. 

**Contacting Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at privacy@redux.com or write to us at: Redux, Inc. Attn: Privacy Officer, 2054 University Suite 200, Berkeley, CA 94704.

**Last Updated: April 3, 2008**
